MOHD FARULLAH BIN HASHIM

Nationality : MALAYSIAN

Age : 26 Gender : Male Marital status : Single

Mobile : +60137910764

Email : farul hashim@yahoo.com

LinkedIn : https://my.linkedin.com/in/farul-hashim-046351b0
Address : https://my.linkedin.com/in/farul-hashim-046351b0
: 587 Felda Tenggaroh 2, 86810 Mersing, Johor Darul Takzim.



SUMMARY

Farullah has about 2 year of working experience; almost 1 year as Electrical Engineer, 6 months of which were in Industrial training dealing with Electrical and Electronic Engineering, 2 month+ in Industrial Training with Sharp Manufacturing (M) Sdn. Bhd in Quality Control Department as well as 2 month+ in IT Industry before continue his study.

Throughout his career, Farullah has been given responsibility as Electrical Engineer. He has experience with intelligent traffic light systems for almost one year. He also responsible as **Project Engineer** that involved to assisting in preparations of staffing, deployment, support plan and check point review during project phase. Furthermore, he also lead the planning and implementation of the project also developing full scale project plan. He also did to manage day to day operational and scheduling project timelines. Farullah also has experience as IT Support and Product Executive which are dealing with as IT Support and Product Executive, which are dealing with Computer Aided Design (CAD) software such as AutoCAD and ZwCAD including software installation, analyzing and troubleshooting issues reported by customers and application users as well as performing bug fixing and verification.

While his main functional strength is on **Electronic Engineering**, he is also well versed with other area such as Computer Networking, CAD (AutoCAD & ZwCAD) and PC Troubleshooting.

He is **CIPA, CIPE and IPC Certified** as well as graduated with an honor degree in Electronic & Computer Engineering with specialization in wireless communication. He is definitely an enthusiastic learner who is looking for a position to capitalize his skills and develop skill set further.

EDUCATION

Sept 2011-June2014 Universiti Teknikal Malaysia Melaka(UTeM)

Bachelor in Electronic Engineering(wireless communication)

July 2008-July 2011 Universiti Teknikal Malaysia Melaka(UTeM)

Diploma in Electronic and Computer Engineering

EXPERIENCE

PPK Technology Sdn Bhd

Role : Electrical Engineer

Duration : August 2015 – Present

Contribution:

- Experience traffic light systems for almost one year.
- Testing controller and setting the timing on junction based on the client suggestion.
- Responsible as Project Engineer to assist in preparations of staffing, deployment, support plan and check point review during project phase.
- Lead the planning and implementation of the project.
- Develop full scale project plan and schedule project timelines.
- Manage day to day operational.
- Scheduling project timelines.

Times the Bookshop Pte Ltd

Role : Supervisor

Duration: November 2014 – August 2015

Contribution:

- Handling the customer demand and problems.
- Documentation for receiving product until return the product.
- Organized and dividing tasks between employees.
- Learn quickly about the Times procedures and concepts to train the new staff.
- Provide the tools for the upcoming event at Sunway Giza on December 2014.

AdvanLED Sdn Bhd

Role : Industrial Trainee

Duration: June 2013 - August 2013

Contribution:

- Troubleshooting circuit and define the problem.
- Doing basic wiring of LED lamp.
- Documentation and making a work instruction (WI) for the new product.
- Organized and updates the WI instruction..

Cadfocus Sdn Bhd

Role : IT support and Product Executive

Duration : July 2011 - August 2011

Contribution:

- Maintain and troubleshoot computers
- Solving customer problem regarding CAD software installation bug fixing and verification
- Provide documentation and tools for software workshop 'AutoCAD'.
- Provide the tools for the upcoming event at KLCC on August 2011.

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Software/Desktop Applications

- Microsoft office word, excel, power point, publisher
- Operating System Windows XP, Window 7, Window 8 and Linux.
- Computer Aided Design (CAD) AutoCAD, ZwCAD and BrisCAD.
- o **MULTISIM**
- o MATLAB
- Adobe Photoshop

Hardware

- Function generator, Oscilloscope and Digital voltmeters.
- Measure or display output in oscilloscope and be familiar with function generator.
- o Known about the component in electronics and trouble shooting.
- o Measure voltage, current, and resistor.
- o Construct wiring up to tree phase

CERTIFIED

- Green Card (CIDB)
- Certified IP Engineer (CIPE) July 2014.
- Certified IP Associate (CIPA) June 2014.
- Acceptability of Electronic Assemblies by Institute of Printed Circuits (IPC) Specialist.

EXTRA CURRICULUM

- Member of Final Year Project program, "INOTECH" at UTeM.
- Member of Basic Entrepreneurship Multimedia Workshop Series 1, South Zone 2014
- Committee of Special Meeting with the Director of Seranta FELDA 2014
- o Committee of the Launching, "'Program Bersama Melestari Transformasi Persada UTeM 2013".
- o Committee of the "Program Memperkasa Penggerak Transformasi Persada 2011".

REFERENCES

- 1. **Mrs. Yusmarnita Binti Yusop**, Lecturer, Faculty of Electronic and Computer Engineering, Universiti Teknikal Malaysia Melaka, 76109 Durian Tunggal, Melaka. **Email**: yusmarnita@utem.edu.my, **Tel**: 019-2391079
- 2. **Nor Farhana Hizami Binti Mohtar**, Retail Executive, Times the Bookstore, Sunway Giza, Petaling Jaya, Kota Damansara, Kuala Lumpur. **Email**: anna.hizamie87@googlemail.com, **Tel**: 012-4193487